Ing. Jakub Pištěk

Pod Harfou 25 190 00 Prague 9



pistekjakub@gmail.com +420 606 883 909

OVERVIEW

Core skills I am very good at solving complex problems in front-end web development with responsive designs from user's

perspective . In back-end I have been using actively a microservice architecture for the last 2 years. My strength is design and development of microservices using appropriate data structures and algorithms.

Areas of interest Software fullstack development, I like learning new frameworks for an inspiration and writing automation tools

to make feature delivery simpler

EDUCATION

2011 - 2013 Czech Technical University, Faculty of Informatics: Knowledge engineering (M.Sc. degree)

2008 - 2011 Czech Technical University, Faculty of Electrical Engineering: Software engineering (B.Sc. degree)

2004 - 2008 Secondary Technical School focused on Software development, Databases and Networking

WORK EXPERIENCE

11/2017 - now Senior Web developer, InnerWorkings

(3000 - 4000 employees)

Developing VALO Portal and other supplying projects using agile (scrum) methodology that covers marketing execution and helps to match Fortune 500 brands with the best suppliers around the world. Presenting new features to project stakeholders.

.NET CORE, MICROSERVICES, SERVICE FABRIC, REACT, REDUX, LESS, MSSQL, KAFKA, MINIO, REDIS,

JENKINS, DOCKER, KUBERNETES

7/2015 - 10/2017 Web developer, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty Inc.

(200 - 500 employees)

Development and maintenance of Pangea CMS and responsive front-end for journalists. Pangea CMS enables to publish multimedia content in 28 languages and allows to connect with more than 30 social networks.

ASP.NET WEBFORMS, ASP.NET MVC, MSSQL, ADO.NET, LESS, GIT

1/2015 - 6/2015 Senior ASP.NET MVC developer, ePojisteni.cz s.r.o.

(150 - 200 employees)

Building a web application which allows to compare over 500 insurance products. .NET, ASP.NET MVC, LINQ2SQL, MSSQL, QUARTZ.NET, ABCPDF.NET, LESS, GIT

1/2014 - 1/2015

ASP.NET WebForms developer, Creasoft s.r.o

(20 - 25 employees)

Development and maintenance of two company core products targeted on customers from financial sector such as banks, pension funds, financial intermediaries, advisors/consultants and insurance companies.

ASP.NET WEBFORMS, MSSQL, LESS, TWITTER BOOTSTRAP 3, ADO.NET, TELERIK WEB CONTROLS, TFS

12/2010 - 1/2014

Junior ASP.NET WebForms and MVC developer, Schneedorfer s.r.o

(5 - 10 employees)

Part of a team working on automated Internet data-crawler. I was responsible for migrating data from slow relational databases to graph database (neo4j). Apart of that I have built few e-shops and improved our CMS. ASP.NET WEBFORMS, ASP.NET MVC, ENTITY FRAMEWORK, ADO.NET, MSSQL, NEO4J, d3.js, nvd3.js, CSS, SVN

TECHNOLOGY OVERVIEW

Front-end JS, REACT, TYPESCRIPT, CSS, LESS, ANTD, BOOTSTRAP RESPONSIVE DESIGN, KNOCKOUT, AMPLIFY,

UNDERSCORE

Back-end .NET CORE, MICROSERVICES, ASP.NET SERVER CONTROLS, EPISERVER FRAMEWORK, KAFKA

Version Control Systems

SVN, TFS, GIT

Databases MS SQL, MYSQL, MINIO, REDIS, GRAPH DATABASES (NEO4J)

Specialities Software development, Responsive design, Machine learning and data mining alghorithms, Collaborative

filtering algorithms, Business intelligence, Nature inspired algorithms

KNOWLEDGE AND SKILLS

Languages Czech (native), English (fluent), Russian (B1), German (A2)

Interests Cycling, Winter sports, Climbing, Traveling and gardening

Other Driver's licence B